Wilcox, Bertram F. Arbitration Awards 5394
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Bertram F. Wilcox Arbitration Awards
1958-1972
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Willcox, Bertram F.
5394
3.5 cubic feet
3.5 linear ft.
Case files, decisions, transcripts.
Case files include awards (and drafts); correspondence regarding individual cases; manuscript notes kept by Willcox on the cases; opinions; arbitrator's reports; grievance reports; agreements; union statements; summaries of testimony; briefs; decisions; transcripts of cases; exhibits; press releases; and other supporting documentation.
2295990
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 03, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Bertram Francis Willcox, (B.A., Cornell University, 1917, LL.B., Harvard University, 1922) was a professor emeritus of law at Cornell University, where he taught most of his academic career (1946-1967).
Willcox was also the McRoberts professor in the administration of law at Cornell (1954-1967). Prior to his teaching career, Willcox practiced with Hughes, Rounds, Schurman & Dwight and was a partner in Schurman, Wiley & Willcox and successor firms (1923-1943). Professor Willcox also served as a public member of the Appeals Board of the US War Labor Board (1944-1945) and as an independent arbitrator.
Scope and Contents
Case files include awards (and drafts); correspondence regarding individual cases; manuscript notes kept by Willcox on the cases; opinions; arbitrator's reports; grievance reports; agreements; union statements; summaries of testimony; briefs; decisions; transcripts of cases; exhibits; press releases; and other supporting documentation.
The major cases arbitrated involve the International Association of Machinists (1950-1958) vs. the following: National Cash Register Company, United States Hoffman Machinery Corporation, American La France, Ward La France, New York Air Brakes Company, Geneva Forge Division of Ekco Products Company, Poloran Products of Pennsylvania, Twin Coach Company, and St. Regis Paper Company. Issues include dismissal, wage rate, time standards, retroactivity, merit pay, incentive rate, recall, and back pay; the International Chemical Workers Union (1950-1960) vs. ANSCO (division of General Anihine and Film Corporation), the Norich Pharmaceutical Company, Winthrop Laboratories (division of Sterling Drug Incorporated), and the George Breon Company on issues of dismissal, wage rate, back pay, incentive rates, seniority (ability and qualifications), promotion, recall, and penalty overtime; and the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen and Helpers of America (1948-1950) vs. Hall's Motor Transit Company, Niagara Motor Express, and Canada Dry Ginger Ale Incorporated on issues of dismissal, recall, and wage rates.
Other cases include the International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America (1953-1955) vs. Pratt and Letchworth (division of the Dayton Malleable Iron Company) and Philco Food Corporation on issues of wages, hours of work, and layoff; United Steelworkers of America (1954-1958) vs. Barcolo Manufacturing Company and Bendix Aviation Corporation (Utica Division) on issues of dismissal, job performance by foremen, seniority, and demotion; the International Handbag and Novelty Workers Union (1954-1955) vs. R. Appeal Incorporated on the issue of dismissal; the United Papermakers and Paperworkers (1958-1969) vs. International Paper Company (Ticonderoga Mills, Northern Division) and St. Regis Paper Company on issues of shift rotation and work days; the United Mine Workers of America, District 50 (1968) vs. Industrial Chemical Division of Allied Chemical Corporation and Pennwoven Incorporated on issues of wage rates, and work assignment; the Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators, and Paperhangers of America (1951-1969) vs. Southern Tier Builders Association and American La France-Foamite Corporation on issues of wages, reclassification, and breach of contract (failure to supply necessary labor); and the United Automobile Workers of America (1955-1969) vs. LeRoy Machine Company and Electric Autolite Company on issues of layoff and contracting out.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Cases; Industrial arbitrators; Arbitration, Industrial -- Aircraft industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Building trades -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Drug trade -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Food industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Handbag industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Iron industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Machine industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Mining industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Novelty industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Paper industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Transportation -- United States; Contracting out -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Employees, Dismissal of -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Hours of labor -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Labor discipline -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Layoffs -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Position classification -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Promotions -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Seniority, Employee -- Law and legislation -- United States; Wages -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Work assignments -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Employee rules -- United States; American La France; Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators, and Paperhangers of America; International Association of Machinists; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America; International Chemical Workers Union; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America; National Cash Register Company; Southern Tier Builders Association; St. Regis Paper Company; United Steelworkers of America; Willcox, Bertram F.
2295990
- R. Appel Incorporated versus International Handbag and Novelty Workers, American Federation of Labor - Correspondence, Documentation, and Notes (Manuscript) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Globe Forge, Incorporated versus United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America, Local 323 - General Correspondence, Documentation, and Manuscript Notes and Drafts (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The Electric Autolite Company versus The International Union United Auto Workers Local 964 - General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Electric Autolite Company versus International Union United Auto Workers Local 964 - Documentation and Manuscript Notes (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Electric Autolite Company versus International Union United Auto Workers Local 964 - Documentation (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The National Cash Register Company versus the International Association of Machinists - Letters (Box 1, Folder 6)
- National Cash Register Company versus International Association of Machinists - Documentation (Box 1, Folder 7)
- National Cash Register Company versus International Association of Machinists - Manuscript Notes and Drafts (Box 1, Folder 8)
- International Chemical Workers Union, Local Number 306 versus Ansco, A Division of General Aniline and Film Corporation - General Correspondence, Documentation, Manuscript Notes and Drafts (Box 1, Folder 9)
- International Chemical Workers Union Local Number 306 versus Ansco, a Division of General Aniline and Film Corporation - Documentation (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ensco - Documentation (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Ansco - Manuscript Notes and Drafts (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Ansco - Manuscript Notes and Drafts (Box 1, Folder 13)
- International Association of Machinists Lodge 396 versus Saint Regis Paper Company Oswego Paper Mill - Letters (Box 2, Folder 1)
- International Association of Machinists Lodge 396 versus Saint Regis Paper Company Oswego Paper Mill - Documentation (Box 2, Folder 2)
- International Association of Machinists Lodge 396 versus Saint Regis Paper Company Oswego Paper Mill - Manuscript Notes and Drafts (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Twin Coach Company - Buffalo Division versus District Lodge 76, Local 1814 International Association of Machinists - Letters (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Twin Coach Company - Buffalo Division versus District Lodge 76, Local 1814, International Association of Machinists - Documentation (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Twin Coach Company - Buffalo Division versus District Lodge 76, Local 1814, International Association of Machinists - Manuscript Notes and Drafts (Box 2, Folder 6)
- General Electric Corporation Schenectady, New York versus United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United states and Canada, Local Number 128 - Letters (Box 2, Folder 7)
- General Electric Corporation Schenectady, New York versus United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United states and Canada, Local Number 128 - Documentation (Box 2, Folder 8)
- General Electric Corporation Schenectady, New York versus United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United states and Canada, Local Number 128 - Documentation (Box 2, Folder 9)
- General Electric Corporation Schenectady, New York versus United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United states and Canada, Local Number 128 - Documentation (Box 2, Folder 10)
- General Electric Corporation Schenectady, New York versus United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United states and Canada, Local Number 128 - Documentation (Box 2, Folder 11)
- General Electric Corporation Schenectady, New York versus United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United states and Canada, Local Number 128 - Documentation (Box 2, Folder 12)
- General Electric Corporation Schenectady, New York versus United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United states and Canada, Local Number 128 - Documentation (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Arbitration File Number 70A/5696. Southern Tier Builder's Association versus Building, Heavy and Highway Construction Local Number 621, Laborers International Union of North America, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Arbitration File Number 69A/5856. Southern Tier Builders Association, Incorporated versus Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators, and Paperhangers of America, Local Union Number 415, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- The Potsdam College Development Fund, Incorporated, of the State University College, Potsdam, New York, versus Civil Service Employee Association, Incorporated, Potsdam College Food Service Chapter, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Arbitration File Number 68A/4133. Poloron Products of Pennsylvania, Incorporated versus the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Anthracite District Number 128, Local Number 868, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Arbitration File Number 68/A5406.Philco Ford Corporation versus the International Union of Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Scope and Contents
  Settled without arbitration
- Arbitration File Number 69A/7357. PPG Industries, Incorporated versus Allied Chemical and Alkali Workers, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Arbitration File Numbers F-41159 and F-41314. Le Roy Machine Company, Incorporated versus the International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, Local Number 481, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Arbitration File Number 69A/789. Kennametal, Incorporated versus Local Union Number 502, United Plant Guard Workers of America, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Patterson Sargent Company versus Local 260, United Glass, Coke, and Chemical Workers of America, Congress of Industrial Organizations - Letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Patterson Sargent Company versus Local 260, United Glass, Coke, and Chemical Workers of America, Congress of Industrial Organizations - Manuscript notes and drafts (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Patterson Sargent Company versus Local 260, United Glass, Coke, and Chemical Workers of America, Congress of Industrial Organizations - Documentation (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Tioga Mills, Incorporated versus American Federation of Grain Processors, Local 22682, American Federation of Labor - Letters (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Tioga Mills, Incorporated versus American Federation of Grain Processors, Local 22682, American Federation of Labor - Documentation (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Tioga Mills, Incorporated versus American Federation of Grain Processors, Local 22682, American Federation of Labor - Manuscript Notes and Drafts (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Canada Dry Ginger Ale, Incorporated versus the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Local 118, American Federation of Labor - Letters (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Canada Dry Ginger Ale, Incorporated versus the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Local 118, American Federation of Labor - Letters, Documentation, Manuscript Notes and Drafts (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Canada Dry Ginger Ale, Incorporated versus the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, Local 118, American Federation of Labor - Manuscript Notes and Drafts (Box 4, Folder 9)
- The Western Express Company versus the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, American Federation of Labor Local 118 - Letters (Box 4, Folder 10)
- The Western Express Company versus the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, American Federation of Labor Local 118 - Documentation (Box 4, Folder 11)
- The Western Express Company versus the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America, American Federation of Labor Local 118 - Manuscript Notes (Box 4, Folder 12)
- District 50, United Mine Workers of America Local Union Number 12318 versus Pennwoven, Incorporated (Lock Haven, Pennsylvania) - Letters (Box 4, Folder 13)
- District 50, United Mine Workers of America Local Union Number 12318 versus Pennwoven, Incorporated (Lock Haven, Pennsylvania) (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Hall's Motor Transit Company (Rochester, New York) versus the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America Local 118 American Federation of Labor - Letters (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Hall's Motor Transit Company (Rochester, New York) versus the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America Local 118 American Federation of Labor - Documentation (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Hall's Motor Transit Company (Rochester, New York) versus the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America Local 118 American Federation of Labor - Manuscript Notes and Drafts (Box 4, Folder 17)
- American-La France-Foamite Corporation (Elmira, New York) and the Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators, and Paperhangers of America and its Local Number 1110 of Elmira, New York - Letters (Box 4, Folder 18)
- American-La France-Foamite Corporation (Elmira, New York) and the Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators, and Paperhangers of America and its Local Number 1110 of Elmira, New York - Documentation (Box 4, Folder 19)
- American-La France-Foamite Corporation (Elmira, New York) and the Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators, and Paperhangers of America and its Local Number 1110 of Elmira, New York - Manuscript Notes (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Arbitration File Number 68A/3515. American Standard Company (Louisville, Kentucky) versus Louisville District Council of Woodworkers (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Withdrawn
- Arbitration File Number 69A/1751. International Paper Company, Ticonderoga Mill, Northern Division versus United Papermakers and Paperworkers Local Number 497 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Arbitration File Number A71-1659. Gellman Industries, Incorporated versus Joint Board Fur, Leather and Machine Workers Union - United Mechanics 150 Division, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Case Number PERB A72-53. Fulton City Schools versus the Fulton Teachers Association (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Arbitration File Number 68A/5666. Eaton Yale and Towne, Incorporated (Trojan Division, Bastavia, New York) versus International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Shipbuilders, Blacksmiths, Forgers, and Helpers, Local Lodge Number 78. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Arbitration File Number A70-180. D'Armigene versus Local 107, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Arbitration File Number A71-49. Buffalo Board of Education versus Buffalo Teachers Federation (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Case Number 1503909111068. International Union of District 50, United Mine Workers of America, Local Number 12457 versus Industrial Chemicals Division, Allied Chemical Corporation (Box 5, Folder 8)
- City School District of the City of Albany, New York versus Albany Public School Teachers Association, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Carrier Corporation versus Sheet Metal Workers Local 527, Syracuse, New York, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Local Number 316, International Union of Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations versus Pratt and Letchworth Division of the Dayton Malleable Iron Company, Incorporated, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Ecko Products Company (Chicago, Illinois) versus International Association of Machinists, Geneva Lodge 2072, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- General Aniline and Film Corporation and its Ansco Division (Binghamton, New York) versus International Chemical Workers Union Local 306, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (Binghamton, New York), 1960 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- New York Air Brake Company, Watertown Division versus the International Association of Machinists Lodge Number 761, District Number 137, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Master Builders Association versus The Bricklayers Trust, Bricklayers - Masons and Plasterers International Union Local 17 (New York), 1960 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- International Chemical Workers Union, Local 306, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations versus General Aniline and Film Corporation, Ansco Division, Binghamton New York, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Winthrop Laboratories, Division of Sterling Drug, Incorporated and the George A. Breon Company versus International Chemical Workers Union, Local Number 61, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Rollway Bearing Company, Incorporated versus International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, United Auto Workers - Congress of Industrial Organizations, Local 798 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Arbitration File Number 59A/324. Barcalo Manufacturing Company versus Steelworkers of America Local 2881 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- International Association of Machinists Local Lodge Number 421, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations versus Ward La France Truck Corporation (Box 6, Folder 11)
- American La France versus Local 421, International Association of Machinists, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Arbitration File Number 58A/1048. United Papermakers and Paperworkers Local Number 45, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations versus Saint Regis Paper Company (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Arbitration File Number 58A/1446. Local Number 251, International Chemical Workers Union, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations versus Norwich Pharmacal Company, Incorporated (Box 6, Folder 14)
- United States Hoffman Machinery Corporation versus Local Lodge Number 847, District Lodge Number 128, International Association of Machinists, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Bendix Aviation Corporation, Utica Division versus United Steelworkers of America Local Union Number 4831, Congress of Industrial Organizations (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 2)